[
{
"question":"Which class cannot be subclassed (or extended) in Java?",
"answer":"Final class",
"option":[ "abstract class","parent class","Final class","None of above"]
},
{
"question":"Can we declare abstract static method?",
"answer":"No",
"option":[ "Yes","No"]
},
{
"question":" Can we access private class outside the package",
"answer":"No",
"option":[ "Yes","No"]
}, 
{
"question":"Why we use array as a parameter of main method?",
"answer":"Can store multiple values",
"option":[ "it is syntax","Can store multiple values","Both of above","None of above"]
},
{
"question":"Suspend thread can be revived by using",
"answer":"resume() method",
"option":[ "start() method","Suspend() method","resume() method","yield() method"]
},  
{
"question":" Runnable is",
"answer":"Interface",
"option":[ "Class","Method","Variable","Interface"]
},
{
"question":" Which collection class associates values with keys, and orders the keys according to their natural order?",
"answer":"java.util.TreeMap",
"option":[ "java.util.HashSet","java.util.LinkedList","java.util.TreeMap","java.util.SortedSet"]
},
{
"question":"  Which method is used to perform DML statements in JDBC?",
"answer":"executeUpdate()",
"option":[ "execute()","executeUpdate()","executeQuery()","None of above"]
},  
{
"question":" Which of the following below are valid isolation levels in J2EE?",
"answer":"Both A and B",
"option":[ "TRANSACTION_READ_UNCOMMITTED","TRANSACTION_SERIALIZABLE","Only A","Both A and B"]
},
{
"question":"Session beans are created by the client submitting the query to the database",
"answer":"True",
"option":[ "True","False"]
},  
{
"question":" Which methods are utilized to control the access to an object in multi threaded programming?",
"answer":"Synchronized methods",
"option":[ "Asynchronized methods","Synchronized methods","Serialized methods","None of above"]
},  
{
"question":"In Runnable, many threads share the same object instance",
"answer":"True",
"option":[ "True","False"]
}, 
{
"question":"In Runnable, many threads share the same object instance",
"answer":"True",
"option":[ "True","False"]
},
{
"question":"Java beans have no types",
"answer":"True",
"option":[ "True","False"]
},
{
"question":"Program which executes applet is known as",
"answer":"applet engine",
"option":[ "applet engine","virtual machine","JVM","None of above"]
},
{
"question":" Which statement is static and synchronized in JDBC API?",
"answer":"getConnection()",
"option":[ "executeQuery()","executeUpdate()","getConnection()","prepareCall()"]
},
{
"question":"Which access specifiers can be used with top level class ?",
"answer":"public or default",
"option":[ "public or default","public or private","public or protected","protected or default"]
},
{
"question":"Which of the following can be marked static ?",
"answer":"Methods , Variables , Initialization Blocks and nested Classes",
"option":[ "Methods , Variables and Initialization Blocks","Methods , Variables , Initialization Blocks and Outer Classes and nested Classes","Methods , Variables , Initialization Blocks and Outer Classes.","Methods , Variables , Initialization Blocks and nested Classes"]
},
{
"question":"Which of the following cannot be marked static ?",
"answer":"Constructors , Classes ( Outer ) , Interfaces , Local variables , Inner Class methods and instance variables",
"option":[ "Constructors , Classes ( Outer ) , Classes ( nested ), Interfaces , Local variables , Inner Class methods and instance variables","Constructors , Classes ( Outer ) , Interfaces , Local variables , Class variables , Class Methods , Inner Class methods and instance variables","Constructors , Classes ( Outer ) , Interfaces , Local variables , Inner Class methods and instance variables","Constructors , Classes ( Outer ) , Classes (Nested), Interfaces , Local variables , Inner Class methods and instance variables"]
},
{
"question":" Which of the following collection maintain its elements in Natural Sorted order ? ",
"answer":"TreeMap",
"option":[ "HashMap","TreeMap","LinkedHashMap","LinkedMap"]
},
{
"question":"Which of the following collections stores its elements in insertion Order ?",
"answer":"LinkedHashMap",
"option":[ "HashMap","TreeMap","LinkedHashMap","LinkedMap"]
},
{
"question":"If we add Enum constants to a sorted collection ( Treemap , TreeSet ), What will be the order in which they will be maintained ?",
"answer":"Order in which constants are declared",
"option":[ "Sorted Collection wont maintain them in any order.","Insertion Order","Order in which constants are declared.","Natural Sorting Order"]
},
{
"question":"In what order the elements of a HashSet are retrieved ?",
"answer":"Random Order",
"option":[ "Random Order"," Insertion Order","Natural Sorting Order","Inverse Natural Sorting Order"]
},
{
"question":"Which of the following was not introduced with Java 5 ?",
"answer":"Strings within Switch",
"option":[ "Generics","Strings within Switch","Enums","Annotations"]
},
{
"question":"Which interface does java.util.Hashtable implement ?",
"answer":"Map",
"option":[ "List","Set","Collection","Map"]
},
{
"question":"Which of the collections allows null as the key ?",
"answer":"HashTable",
"option":[ "HashTable","HashMap","TreeMap","LinkedHashMap"]
},
{
"question":"What is the initial state of a thread when it is created and started ?",
"answer":"Ready",
"option":[ "Wait","Running","Ready","Sleep"]
},
{
"question":"What state does a thread enter when it terminates its processing?",
"answer":"Dead",
"option":[ "Wait","Running","Ready","Dead"]
},
{
"question":"How many bits are used to represent Unicode ?",
"answer":"16 bits",
"option":[ "8 bits","16 bits","24 bits","32 bits"]
},
{
"question":"Which keyword is used to provide explicit access of a code block to single thread ?",
"answer":"Synchronized",
"option":[ "Transient","Final","Explicit","Synchronized"]
},
{
"question":"Which of the following exception is thrown when we try to access element which is beyond the size ?",
"answer":"ArrayIndexOutOfBoundException",
"option":[ "NullPointerException","ArrayIndexOutOfBoundException","ArithmeticException","ParseException"]
},
{
"question":"Checked exception needs to be ... ",
"answer":"Either A or B",
"option":[ "Caught","Method needs to declare that it throws these exception","Either A or B","Both A and B"]
},
{
"question":"Collections.sort can only be performed on ..",
"answer":"List",
"option":[ "Set","List","Map","Any Collection implementation"]
},
{
"question":"Variables of an interface are intrinsically ...",
"answer":"transient",
"option":[ "transient","final","public","static"]
},
{
"question":"Which of the following class creates mutable objects ?",
"answer":"StringBuffer",
"option":[ "Boolean","File","String","StringBuffer"]
},
{
"question":"Invoking start twice on same thread leads to ..",
"answer":"IllegalStateException",
"option":[ "ClassCastException","NullPointerException","InterruptedException","IllegalStateException"]
},
{
"question":"Which of the following doesn't extend Collection interface ?",
"answer":"Map",
"option":[ "Set","List","Map","Queue"]
},
{
"question":"Which method is called first by an applet program?",
"answer":"init()",
"option":[ "start()","run()","init()","begin()"]
},
{
"question":"A constructor that is automatically generated in the absence of explicit constructors called?",
"answer":"All the above",
"option":[ "Default Constructor","Nullary Constructor","Empty Constructor","All the above"]
},
{
"question":"Choose best option that describes Constructor",
"answer":"Use name of the class and have no return type",
"option":[ "Have no return type","Use name of the class and have no return type","Use name of the class","None of the above"]
},
{
"question":"Overloaded methods are differentiated by",
"answer":"Number and the Data type of the arguments",
"option":[ "Number of arguments","Data type of arguments","Number and the Data type of the arguments","None of the above"]
},
{
"question":"Which keyword is used to inherit class?",
"answer":"extends",
"option":[ "inherit","extends","inheritance","extend"]
},
{
"question":"Which method of System class is used to copy array?",
"answer":"arraycopy",
"option":[ "copyArray","arrayCopy","arraycopy","arrCopy"]
},
{
"question":"Which is not a valid keyword in java?",
"answer":"null",
"option":[ "null","transient","synchronized","native"]
},
{
"question":"Unchecked exceptions are checked at compile-time rather they are checked at runtime",
"answer":"False",
"option":[ "True","False"]
},
{
"question":"The PipedInputStream and PipedOutputStream classes can be used to read and write data simultaneously",
"answer":"True",
"option":[ "True","False"]
},
{
"question":"ResultSetMetaData interface is useful because it provides methods to get metadata from the ResultSet object",
"answer":"True",
"option":[ "True","False"]
},
{
"question":" How many reserved keywords are currently defined in the Java language?",
"answer":"49",
"option":[ "48","49","50","47"]
},
{
"question":"Which mechanism is used when a thread is paused while running in its critical section and another thread is allowed to enter (or lock) in the same critical section to be executed?",
"answer":"Inter-thread communication",
"option":[ "Inter-thread communication","Initial-thread communication","Mutual Exclusive","None of the above"]
}
]
